# Karen Herrera

Software Engineer

(+57) 301-2050921 karenahv@gmail.com https://github.com/Karenahv https://www.linkedin.com/in/karenherreravega

Industrial Engineer, Self-driven Software developer and Project Manager (PMI) with more than 4 years developing web and mobile applications using React.js, Next.js, React Native, Stencil and NodeJs. I have an entrepreneurship mindset which is why I have worked also in startups leading teams and building web and mobile applications that today are used by thousands of people in Latin America. I'm a goal-oriented, great team worker with good communication skills and knowledge of business-related topics. Also, I consider myself a self-taught learning enthusiast, there have never been excuses when learning something new. Recently I have been trying new technologies like Golang and Machine Learning.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## ADDI - August 2021 - Present

Frontend Software Engineer

- Develop new features, improvements or fix bugs in the mobile application, web applications and widgets (web components).
- Also in Addi we are responsible for creating all the planning needed to develop the feature and create the release plans for each feature that is sent to production
- Monitoring the features in production

○ Tech-Stack: : | HTML | CSS | React native | React js | Next js | Stencil js | Typescript | Redux | Java | Project Reactor | PostgreSQL

## Globant Inc — Mayo 2021 - August 2021

Front end developer

• As a software developer I am transforming designs into pixel perfect components and turning ideas into MVP's using cutting-edge technology and clean and functional UI/UX design.

○ Tech-Stack: : | HTML | CSS Reactjs | Nextjs | Javascript | NodeJs

## Grovity Inc — August 2019 - Abril 2021

Partner- Frontend Engineer - Team Lead.

- Planned, designed, and developed a web application from zero to deploy by using agile methodologies and design patterns embracing flexible, maintainable and reusable codebases. This application is used by +3.000 people approximately.
- Improved the usability with daily improvements on the front end and back end, reaching more than 90% Customer Effort Service.
- Developed a chat-bot that has improved the support time response in 90%.
- Development of dashboards, forms and integrations with technologies and information multi-tenant using Reactjs that allow to launch a new business model line in 2021.

○ Tech-Stack: JavaScript | ReactJS | NodeJS | Golang | PostgreSQL | Redux | Aws | HTML | CSS

## **Independent Software Developer (Remote)** — May 2019 - Present

Freelancer

Planned, designed, and developed 2 web applications from zero to deploy by using agile methodologies and design patterns
embracing flexible, maintainable and reusable codebases in logistics and Data Analysis sectors.

## **FREELANCER - OTHER RELATED PROJECTS**

January 2019-August 2019

Servienvios - https://www.servienvios.co/

Logistics Web Application

- Planned, designed, and developed a web application that allows customers to track their shipments and quote new services online.
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, Django, PostgreSQL, Redux, Heroku, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Restserver NodeJS - https://restserver-node-karen.herokuapp.com/

 Developed a complete ecommerce backend in nodeJs, with JWT token authentication, models like users, categories and products.

○ **Tech-Stack:** JavaScript, NodeJS, MongoDB, Express

#### **SKILLS**

**Proficient:** Python, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, NextJS, HTML, CSS, NodeJS Agile Methodologies, Heroku, API REST, PostgreSQL. **Familiar**: MongoDB, Django, Flask, Golang, Machine learning, AWS.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Fluent; Spanish, Native;

#### **EDUCATION**

Udemy Courses – more than 10 courses finished related to the Front end fields.

Bootcamp Holberton School – Bogotá, Colombia.

Full stack Software Developer, May 2019 - December 2019

Bootcamp Make it Real – Bogotá, Colombia.

Web-development, January 2019 - May-2019

Escuela Colombiana de Ingeniería "Julio Garavito" – Bogotá, Colombia.

Industrial Engineer and Master in Project Management, March 2015